<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Island94.org Book Reviews</title>
    <description>A Lost and Found
</description>
    <link>https://island94.org/books</link>
    <atom:link href="https://island94.org/books.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 01:50:10 +0000</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Jun 2023 01:50:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.3.2</generator>
    
    
      






<item>
  <title>I read &quot;The Constant Rabbit&quot; by Jasper Fforde</title>
  <description>&lt;p&gt;An “Event” has caused rabbits to become anthropomophic. This exchange is the book in a walnut-shell:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;So while we ate the excellent walnut cake that the Venerable Bunty’s mother’s sister’s daughter’s husband’s son had baked, Venerable Bunty and Connie told us about life inside the colonies, which despite the lack of freedom and limited space were the only areas within the United Kingdom that ran themselves entirely on rabbit socio-egalitarian principles.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;‘It’s occasionally aggressive and often uncompromising,’ said Finkle, ‘but from what I’ve seen of both systems, a country run on rabbit principles would be a step forward – although to be honest, I’m not sure we’d be neurologically suited to the regime. While most humans are wired to be reasonably decent, a few are wired to be utter shits – and they do tend to tip the balance.’&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;‘The decent humans are generally supportive of doing the right thing,’ said the Venerable Bunty, ‘but never take it much farther than that. You’re trashing the ecosystem for no reason other than a deluded sense of anthropocentric manifest destiny, and until you stop talking around the issue and actually feel some genuine guilt, there’ll be no change.’&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;‘Shame, for want of a better word, is good,’ said Finkle. ‘Shame is right, shame works. Shame is the gateway emotion to increased self-criticism, which leads to realisation, an apology, outrage and eventually meaningful action. We’re not holding our breaths that any appreciable numbers can be arsed to make the journey along that difficult chain of emotional honesty – many good people get past realisation, only to then get horribly stuck at apology – but we live in hope.’&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;‘I understand,’ I said, having felt that I too had yet to make the jump to apology.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;‘It’s further evidence of satire being the engine of the Event,’ said Connie, ‘although if that’s true, we’re not sure for whose benefit.’&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;‘Certainly not humans’,’ said Finkle, ‘since satire is meant to highlight faults in a humorous way to achieve betterment, and if anything, the presence of rabbits has actually made humans worse.’&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;‘Maybe it’s the default position of humans when they feel threatened,’ I ventured, ‘although if I’m honest, I know a lot of people who claim to have “nothing against rabbits” but tacitly do nothing against the overt leporiphobia that surrounds them.’&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;‘Or maybe it’s just satire for comedy’s sake and nothing else,’ added Connie, ‘or even more useless, satire that provokes a few guffaws but only low to middling outrage – but is coupled with more talk and no action. A sort of  . . . empty cleverness.’&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;‘Maybe a small puff in the right moral direction is the best that could be hoped for,’ added Finkle thoughtfully. ‘Perhaps that’s what satire does – not change things wholesale but nudge the collective consciousness in a direction that favours justice and equality. Is there any more walnut cake?’&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;‘I’m afraid I had the last slice,’ I said, ‘but I did ask if anyone else wanted it.’&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;hr&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    This book review for &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://island94.org/2023/04/the-constant-rabbit&quot;&gt;The Constant Rabbit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, is published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://island94.org&quot;&gt;Island94.org&lt;/a&gt;.
    Tweet me at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bensheldon&quot;&gt;@bensheldon&lt;/a&gt; to discuss it.
  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
  <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 03:29:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <link>https://island94.org/2023/04/the-constant-rabbit</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="true">https://island94.org/2023/04/the-constant-rabbit</guid>
</item>

    
      






<item>
  <title>I read &quot;The Dawn of Everything&quot; by David Graeber and David Wengrow</title>
  <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;If there is a particular story we should be telling, a big question we should be asking of human history (instead of the ‘origins of social inequality’), is it precisely this: how did we find ourselves stuck in just one form of social reality, and how did relations based ultimately on violence and domination come to be normalized within it?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;What happens if we treat the rejection of urban life, or of slavery, [or of certain technologies] in certain times and places as something just as significant as the emergence of those same phenomena in others.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;What is the purpose of all this new knowledge, if not to reshape our conceptions of who we are and what we might yet become? If not, in other words, to rediscover the meaning of our third basic freedom: the freedom to create new and different forms of social reality?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I imagine I’m already on board with David Graeber’s political project, so while I greatly enjoyed it, I found it too long by about a third.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The overall thrust is that people are much more interesting and creative than we give them credit for, and there’s a lot (too much for me in this book) of historical evidence that this is the case. And that it’s bunk to claim that increasing social complexity and scale requires an authoritarian state or bureacracy. I guess it’s an argument to unstick the “End of History”-framing we’re mired in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of various things I learned / was confronted with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Indulging children is Native American practice. Makes sense cause it’s a common theme in Kim Stanley Robinson books of which the Haudenosaunee make frequent appearance too.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Roman-style property ownership (of which we inherit), is pretty fucked up when stared directly at, based on a patriarch’s relations with household slaves.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It seems like a pretty legit critique of Western society to point out that there are a lot of &lt;em&gt;legitimate&lt;/em&gt; ways poeple are free to harm other people during their every day life, and that’s got to be pretty warpy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Spending more time imagining and debating the society and politics you want to live in… probably makes for a better society and politics. One of those, if it’s hard do it a lot sorts of things. And if that sounds annoying in the context of the present, that’s probably because we’ve severely narrowed the scope of debate and possibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a lot of history and anthropology to boil down:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;…the key point to remember is that we are not talking here about ‘freedom’ as an abstract ideal or formal principle (as in ‘Liberty, Equality and Fraternity!’). Over the course of these chapters we have instead talked about basic forms of social liberty which one might actually put into practice:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;the freedom to move away or relocate from one’s surroundings;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;the freedom to ignore or disobey commands issued by others; and&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;the freedom to shape entirely new social realities, or shift back and forth between different ones&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;….three elementary principles of domination:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;control of violence (or sovereignty),&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;control of knowledge, and&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;charismatic politics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…and a lot of historical and anthropoligical critique:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Environmental determinists have an unfortunate tendency to treat humans as little more than automata, living out some economist’s fantasy of rational calculation. To be fair, they don’t deny that human beings are quirky and imaginative creatures – they just seem to reason that, in the long run, this fact makes very little difference.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;For much of the twentieth century, anthropologists tended to describe the societies they studied in ahistorical terms, as living in a kind of eternal present. Some of this was an effect of the colonial situation under which much ethnographic research was carried out. The British Empire, for instance, maintained a system of indirect rule in various parts of Africa, India and the Middle East where local institutions like royal courts, earth shrines, associations of clan elders, men’s houses and the like were maintained in place, indeed fixed by legislation. Major political change – forming a political party, say, or leading a prophetic movement – was in turn entirely illegal, and anyone who tried to do such things was likely to be put in prison. This obviously made it easier to describe the people anthropologists studied as having a way of life that was timeless and unchanging.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;….&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Social science has been largely a study of the ways in which human beings are not free: the way that our actions and understandings might be said to be determined by forces outside our control. Any account which appears to show human beings collectively shaping their own destiny, or even expressing freedom for its own sake, will likely be written off as illusory, awaiting ‘real’ scientific explanation; or if none is forthcoming (why do people dance?), as outside the scope of social theory entirely. This is one reason why most ‘big histories’ place such a strong focus on technology. Dividing up the human past according to the primary material from which tools and weapons were made (Stone Age, Bronze Age, Iron Age) or else describing it as a series of revolutionary breakthroughs (Agricultural Revolution, Urban Revolution, Industrial Revolution), they then assume that the technologies themselves largely determine the shape that human societies will take for centuries to come – or at least until the next abrupt and unexpected breakthrough comes along to change everything again.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Choosing to describe history the other way round, as a series of abrupt technological revolutions, each followed by long periods when we were prisoners of our own creations, has consequences. Ultimately it is a way of representing our species as decidedly less thoughtful, less creative, less free than we actually turn out to have been. It means not describing history as a continual series of new ideas and innovations, technical or otherwise, during which different communities made collective decisions about which technologies they saw fit to apply to everyday purposes, and which to keep confined to the domain of experimentation or ritual play. What is true of technological creativity is, of course, even more true of social creativity. One of the most striking patterns we discovered while researching this book – indeed, one of the patterns that felt most like a genuine breakthrough to us – was how, time and again in human history, that zone of ritual play has also acted as a site of social experimentation – even, in some ways, as an encyclopaedia of social possibilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;hr&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    This book review for &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://island94.org/2023/04/the-dawn-of-everything&quot;&gt;The Dawn of Everything&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, is published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://island94.org&quot;&gt;Island94.org&lt;/a&gt;.
    Tweet me at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bensheldon&quot;&gt;@bensheldon&lt;/a&gt; to discuss it.
  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
  <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2023 02:56:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <link>https://island94.org/2023/04/the-dawn-of-everything</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="true">https://island94.org/2023/04/the-dawn-of-everything</guid>
</item>

    
      






<item>
  <title>I read &quot;Synectics: The Development of Creative Capacity&quot; by William J. J. Gordon</title>
  <description>&lt;p&gt;This book has big ’60s energy, believing in the creative potential of a group of men openly jawboning in a room (but the prompts!) to solve problems. I’ve also read &lt;em&gt;The Practice of Creativity&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Innovator’s Handbook&lt;/em&gt; too; the former probably being the best of them. They all are mainly persuasive theory and leave me trying to figure out the actual facilitation plans between the lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book as a whole is engaging and has a lot of transcripts of people talking over eachother to solve a problem, as good as any pulp hard/heroic science fiction of the period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is synectics?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The word &lt;em&gt;Synectics&lt;/em&gt;, from the Greek, means the joining together of different and apparently irrelevant elements. Synectics theory applies to the integration of diverse individuals into a problem-stating problem-solving group. It is an operational theory for the conscious use of the preconscious psychological mechanisms present in man’s creative activity. The purpose of developing such a theory is to increase the probability of success in problem-stating, problem-solving situations. This increase depends on awareness of the mechanisms which must be worked through to arrive at solutions of fundamental novelty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And play:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Three general types of mechanisms for play have emerged from these studies: (1) play with words, with meanings and definitions; (2) play in pushing a fundamental law or a basic scientific concept “out of phase”; and (3) play with metaphor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Demo or die:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The most important (and most underrated) single aspect of a Synectics project is the implementation (in the form of working models) of those concepts developed as solutions. Such model building is vital to the success of a new product or invention program. Moreover, we have observed that unless a teaching program includes the experience of “getting the hands dirty” by actively implementing conceptions, the program is threatened with incompletion and impotence precisely because it is limited to over-abstract discussion. …[30 pages]…Exciting as it is for Synectics groups to succeed in making the familiar strange, it is hardly an end in itself. The end is a functioning, working model of the invention product, just as the end result of a narrative idea is not the idea but the novel into which it is transformed, or as the end result of a visual insight is the painting into which it is evolved.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The general idea of a Synectics group (“in the Industrial Model”) is having the company psychologist pick a small group of [men] to go live and cook together and solve problems for the firm. This is interesting:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In the selection of personnel for Synectics activity, if we are faced with a choice between two individuals of different intellectual backgrounds, but of similar emotional orientations, our tendency would be to choose only one. On the other hand, two individuals having the same intellectual background but different emotional patterns of response could be included in an integrated group which is designed to reflect extreme diversity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you choose? Lots of bias here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;1. Metaphoric Capacity: The candidate’s language is carefully watched for signs of metaphor and analogy as described by the operational mechanisms: Personal Analogy, Symbolic Analogy, Direct Analogy, and Fantasy Analogy. The candidate is encouraged to speak metaphorically…&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Attitude of Assistance: Because some characteristics of a candidate can’t be identified from conversation alone, the interview includes taking a walk in the woods, inviting the candidate to participate in a project on the property (pipe is being laid or a little bridge is being built over a stream, or a new timber is being fitted to the bam); in the evening the candidate meets with the Synectors for a cook-out. If his attitude of assistance has not revealed itself before, the cook-out preparation is used as the ultimate test. In general there are three kinds of response to this activity:&lt;/p&gt;

      &lt;ol&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;The candidate sits and watches the fire being laid.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;The candidate asks if he can help.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;The candidate observes what is needed and supplies it.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ol&gt;

      &lt;p&gt;Building a fire is such a universal function, known to everyone, that it serves as an excellent test of assistance attitude. Obviously, for the purpose of Synectics, a man who sees how he can help and does it is the most acceptable. Part of the fire making technique is to make sure that there is not enough kindling on the spot so as to guarantee ample opportunity for the candidate to reveal himself.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;3. Kinesthetic Coordination: Although clumsiness is not inconsistent with creative potential, Synectors guard against selecting a man whose extreme lack of coordination implies a lack of self-confidence. [jesus christ]…&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Risk: In the course of talking to the candidate, Synectors must determine whether he enjoys taking risks and, if so, what kind of risks. Is the candidate a self-destructive gambler who is unconsciously trying to injure himself? Is he willing to risk because he knows it’s the only way to accomplish certain tasks? Does he enjoy risking or does it frighten him?…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;5. Emotional Maturity: Creative people tend to have a childlike quality about them, but this childishness is not necessarily a sign of emotional immaturity. The emotionally immature childlike person does not use his childlike surprise, wonder, and infinite curiosity about the world as a psychological basis for creative acts. It is the capacity to integrate childishness into constructive acts which the Synectors look for in their interviews with candidates….&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;The Capacity to Generalize: What are the candidate’s thinking habits? Can he take three or four facts and construct from them a straightforward, conversational, coherent generalization? Can he oscillate from particular facts to theories which embrace and integrate the facts? A generalization is a hypothesis describing and including diverse and sometimes conflicting data. Can he tolerate the ambiguity with which he must live until a soothing, all-ordering generalization explains the data? And then can he act on the basis of his generalization?…&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Commitment: If the candidate believes in something—product or a concept—can he commit himself to bringing it to life? Or is he self-protectively analytical and falsely sophisticated? The personality characteristic of enthusiasm is not by itself a guarantee. The candidate must identify with a project so that its success is crucial to him…&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Non-status Oriented: There are traditional symbols of status in American industrial society: carpet on the floor, large clean desks, prints on the wall, name on the door, in charge of a large number of men, conservatively natty clothes, new car—these symbolize the position of a man. Minor variations are permitted within the conventions of this framework to describe the residual differences in personalities. People chosen for Synectics activity must be beyond status as defined by the traditional symbolism because their group will develop another kind of status based on contribution and independence…&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Complementary Aspect: No candidate can get a perfect score in all the criteria but the group as a whole should make up 100% of the characteristics implied by the list of criteria. Also, there are certain special personality traits within the candidates which must be balanced. Assume two men who score high, one from research, one from sales. The researcher, introverted and studious, rates the salesman as flamboyant and loud. The salesman calls the researcher mousey and secretive. Each man distrusts the other, yet both are necessary to the success of a Synectics operation. [o_O] Someone must be found who can bring together the researcher and salesman. The Synectors, on the lookout, decide on a man who had been in research but now, for instance, is in sales engineering. This “integrator” is interviewed, not only on the basis of the criteria, but also to learn whether his personality can resolve the conflict between the researcher and the salesman.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what do they do?!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The Synectic process involves:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;making the strange familiar;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;making the familiar strange.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;…Synectics has identified four mechanisms for making the familiar strange, each metaphorical in character:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Personal Analogy [how would you live/feel if you were the subject under study?]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Direct Analogy [“the actual comparison of parallel facts, knowledge, or technology”]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Symbolic Analogy [“views the problem qualitatively with the condensed suddenness of a poetic phrase.”]&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fantasy Analogy [“How do we in our wildest fantasies desire the subject to operate?”]&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh brother.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Every mature institution or organization—industrial, governmental or educational—functions according to laws which make up its policy. For example, every company has its own “laws” about personnel, procurement, borrowing money, sales, production, salaries, quality control, customer relations, product line, budgets, advertising, etc. If the laws represent a true response to reality, they will be useful. But often, particularly in the case of an old established company, the laws are habits carried forward from a glittering past. Long-term employees from a middle management level up constitute an intra-organizational community which derives comfort from these familiar laws—obsolete or not. This community is the keeper of the scrolls. The laws are the anthropological shibboleths by which the industrial tribe conducts its ritual of business. A Synectics group is a fifth column acting from within the organization community to make the familiar “laws” strange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;hr&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    This book review for &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://island94.org/2022/11/synectics&quot;&gt;Synectics: The Development of Creative Capacity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, is published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://island94.org&quot;&gt;Island94.org&lt;/a&gt;.
    Tweet me at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bensheldon&quot;&gt;@bensheldon&lt;/a&gt; to discuss it.
  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 01:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <link>https://island94.org/2022/11/synectics</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="true">https://island94.org/2022/11/synectics</guid>
</item>

    
      






<item>
  <title>I read &quot;Object Thinking&quot; by David West</title>
  <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m looking for a book that helps align the practice of software development with the rest of my life, In the sense of a humanistic neural plasticity, an approach that harmonizes rather than hegemonizes (or ignores) the rest of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This book is based on the following beliefs:&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Agility, especially in the form of extreme programming, is essential if the software development profession, and industry, are to improve themselves.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;XP offers a way to create “better developers” to improve the intrinsic abilities of human beings to develop software for use by other human beings—a way to produce “master” developers.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;XP cannot be understood, and those practicing XP will not realize the full potential of the approach, until they understand object thinking and the shared historical and philosophical roots of both object thinking and XP core values and practices.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;In particular, programmers and technical developers will fail to realize the full potential of XP-based development without a thorough understanding of object orientation—the “object thinking” promised by the title of this book.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I initially found this book searching for “Sapir-Whorf” on the O’Reilly Bookshelf. To the extent that it approaches things humanistically, this is it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inheritance&lt;/strong&gt;: Humans naturally aggregate similar things into sets (or classes). Another “natural” kind of thinking is to create &lt;em&gt;taxonomies&lt;/em&gt;—hierarchical relationships among the sets.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Responsibility&lt;/strong&gt;:  If an object states that it is capable of providing a given service, it should perform that service in all circumstances, and the results should be consistent… Responsibility implies that an object must assume control of itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wasn’t quite the book I wanted, though I enjoyed the introduction and the conclusion. The middle was a bunch of methodology that, well, was fine, but I probably won’t think about again; the conclusion does admit that the methodology and modeling section is written primarily as legitimating material for academic formalists and can be transcended and discarded. So that’s cool (but I would have appreciated that being said upfront than afterwards).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;All methods are someone else’s idea about what you should do when you develop software. It may be useful, from time to time, to borrow from those ideas and integrate them into your own style. It is essential, however, to transcend any method, even your own idiosyncratic method, and “just do it.”&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Software development is like riding a surfboard—there is no process that will assure a successful ride, nor is there any process that will assure that you will interact propitiously with the other surfers sharing the same wave. Published processes, like published methods, provide observational data from which you can learn and thereby improve your innate abilities—just as observation of master surfers enables you to improve yourself.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;No model has any value other than to assist in object thinking and to provide a means for interpersonal communication. If you can model your objects and your scenarios in your head while engaged in writing code, and if those mental models are consistent with object thinking, great! No need to write them down. If you and your colleagues use a visual model on a whiteboard as an aid in talking about scenarios and in clarifying your collective thinking about those scenarios, and you erase the board when you’re done meeting, also great! If your models are crudely drawn and use only a subset of the syntax defined here (or a completely different syntax that you and your colleagues collectively agree upon), still great! Model when you must, what you must, and only what you must.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the good stuff, though it doesn’t have much of a developmental model:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;

  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Decompose the problem space into behavioral objects, and make sure the behaviors assigned to those objects are consistent with user expectations. This requires understanding why users make distinctions among objects and the &lt;em&gt;illusions&lt;/em&gt; they project on those objects. User illusions (following Alan Kay) consist of how people recognize different objects in their world and, having recognized an object, what assumptions are made about how to interact with that object and what its responses will be.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;User illusions should be maintained; your software objects should not violate them unless you can construct a plausible alternative story that shows a different set of domain entities interacting in different ways or having different capabilities. Business reengineering involves exactly this kind of activity—using domain language and user illusions creatively to craft new stories, some of which might lead to new software.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Decompose your problems (applications) in terms of conversations among groups of objects. Everything of interest in the domain is currently accomplished by groups of objects (people and things). Any artifact you construct must participate in a natural way in these same groups. Perhaps your artifact is simply replacing an existing object in the domain with a computer-based simulacrum, in which case it must know how to respond to and supply some relevant subset of recognizable and intuitive interaction cues. Perhaps it is an entirely new object, in which case it will need to be “socialized” to conform to the existing community.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;hr&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    This book review for &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://island94.org/2022/09/object-thinking&quot;&gt;Object Thinking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, is published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://island94.org&quot;&gt;Island94.org&lt;/a&gt;.
    Tweet me at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bensheldon&quot;&gt;@bensheldon&lt;/a&gt; to discuss it.
  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Sep 2022 20:23:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <link>https://island94.org/2022/09/object-thinking</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="true">https://island94.org/2022/09/object-thinking</guid>
</item>

    
      






<item>
  <title>I read &quot;Programmed Inequality: How Britain Discarded Women Technologists and Lost Its Edge in Computing&quot; by Mar Hicks</title>
  <description>&lt;p&gt;The experience of learning about systemic racism in the US is a constant derailing of “but we can’t know the actual intent”; systemic sexism on the otherhand is “oh, here are the receipts”. Which is not to discount the research and scholarship of author Mar Hicks, more just to say “wow, there it is”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Programmed Inequality&lt;/em&gt; is focused on one particular aspect covered by the more surveyish &lt;em&gt;Recoding Gender&lt;/em&gt;. To attempt to summarize a lot:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take a systemic inequality, like the Marriage Bar, which made it unlawful for women to keep their job once they became married.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Then it’s reasonable to imagine that managers will invest less time in training and developing women in the workplace.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Then it’s reasonable to imagine that women are less likely to be promoted into management and leadership.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Then it’s reasonable to imagine that women will be tracked into roles and functions that do not offer training or management potential.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Then it’s reasonable to imagine that roles and functions will be designed and shaped around these constraints and will develop bureacratic inertia.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Then it’s reasonable to imagine that other roles and functions (who happen to be men, because of the previous reasonable assertions) will be bureacratically competing for power and resources and prestige with those feminized roles and functions (and the women who fill them). And it will be ugly.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Then it’s reasonable to imagine that, people being people, on human timescales with human constraints, and talent being equally distributed even when opportunity is not, they’ll do their best to navigate and come to terms with it in different ways.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a book about an 80 year trainwreck. It has some interesting details about deskilling, and also about femininization: how expertise is reframed as “temperment”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Although government reports referred to the great mass of their women workers as doing the “ monotonous toutine work” that made up the broad base of the Civil Service “pyramid,” inquiries into the exact content and nature of machine operation commissioned by the Treasury itself repeatedly contradicted the characterizations of it as deskilled work.” These reports showed how machine workers needed many of the same skill sets as higher clerical workers and how machine operation jobs were best performed by higher-skill, more educated workers. Even machine workers at the lowest levels, who dealt with narrowly specialized calculations, possessed similar skills as clerical workers: “The lower grades of the technical part of the engineering field and the scientific Assistants are both fairly close to the Clerical Class in many respects,” admitted an internal Treasury memo. Despite this, most women workers were now partitioned off from the higher-status clerical class. Eventually, the machine operator class would have three levels: The entry-level rung was the position of machine assistant. The middle rung of machine operator, took on more complex work. Women would rise to machine operator in their midtwenties. The top grade was senior machine operator. These women would perform the most complicated work in the class, including programming and systems analysis. The expectation was for women to attain that rank in their later twenties or early thirties, because at that point promotion and pay increases ceased–much earlier than for workers in clerical jobs. The structure of the new class enforced a shortened, dead-end career, partly because of the idea that women should leave by this point to get married and take care of a family, but also as a reflection of the low worth accorded to this work. Many Civil Service leaders in this era could not conceive of technical or machine-aided office work as interesting, as complex, or as providing preparation for higher work. The fact that the association of women with machine work in offices had initially evolved from women’s association with typewriteers helped reinforce this attitude. Yet the machine class was not simply a reflection of the status quo. It was the Treasury’s attempt to deal with rising numbers of women employees by reorganizing the government’s postwar workforce.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And surfaces a lot of stuff that’s seemingly baked into computing and labor relations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Even before White Heat raised the profile of computing, a 1962 overview of government computing policy reported that the government hoped to recruit most programmers from the ranks of the seventy thousand workers in the executive class–the management class of workers with A-level secondary school training, but without the university training of the higher administrative class or any particular skill set commonly associated with early programming expertise. Executive class officers dealt with long-term departmental goals and developed processes for greater efficiency. They were also overwhelmingly men. Paradoxically, these new recruits were thought to be more qualified for the technical aspects of computer jobs even though they lacked any machine experience. The tacit expectation was that higher-level civil servants would be more intelligent overall and therefore would have no trouble picking up supposedly lowly technical skills. A widespread belief persisted in government that work involving machines did not require much intellect. Yet the Treasury’s initial feelings that “the operation of computers was expected to be similar to that of punched card equipment and thus proper to SMOs [senior machine operators]” was giving way to the idea that computing jobs were actually too complex and required too much training to continue using feminized labor. “ Although a number of staff currently graded in the MO (Machine Operator) class are demonstrably suited to be computer operators,” opined one 1966 report, “it must not be assumed that all machine operators capable of traditional responsibilities for that class have in fact ‘operating’ ability.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This shift in attitude reflected the rigidity of the class hierarchies of the Civil Service. Even though government workers were supposed to be able to rise through the ranks meritocratically, by means of examinations, those in the lower classes of the service were often seen as fundamentally inferior to those at higher levels. As a result, there was little focus on grooming workers already in computer posts for higher positions. Instead “better” workers would be brought in from the executive class and trained to do those jobs. Whether the nation was headed by Labor or the Conservatives, the highest administrators within the service remained relatively constant in their opinions about modernization within government. “It was early on decided that for most programming orderical operations one did not need graduates in mathematics or other Growledge of professional standard, but a reasonable level of intelligence and certain aptitudes,” explained an organization specialist in the Treasury who authored a 1962 report titled “Electronic Computers Oil the Wheels of Government,” Management potential and a broad understanding of the workings of government agencies were the key qualities the Treasury now sought in computer workers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;hr&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    This book review for &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://island94.org/2022/06/programmed-inequality-how-britain-discarded-women-technologists-and-lost-its-edge-in-computing&quot;&gt;Programmed Inequality: How Britain Discarded Women Technologists and Lost Its Edge in Computing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, is published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://island94.org&quot;&gt;Island94.org&lt;/a&gt;.
    Tweet me at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bensheldon&quot;&gt;@bensheldon&lt;/a&gt; to discuss it.
  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
  <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 23:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <link>https://island94.org/2022/06/programmed-inequality-how-britain-discarded-women-technologists-and-lost-its-edge-in-computing</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="true">https://island94.org/2022/06/programmed-inequality-how-britain-discarded-women-technologists-and-lost-its-edge-in-computing</guid>
</item>

    
      






<item>
  <title>I read &quot;Hench&quot; by Natalie Zina Walschots</title>
  <description>&lt;p&gt;Hench moves past &lt;a href=&quot;https://tvtropes.org/pmwiki/pmwiki.php/Main/BewareTheSuperman&quot;&gt;“but what if superheroes were actually bad?”&lt;/a&gt; and into exploring whether one can have superpowers without aligning/performing as a hero (not according to the heroes) and can someone be villaneous without being evil? (open question)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s delightful in the Becky Chambers’-style of “let’s (try) to be our best selves while navigating our differences against a backdrop of adversity”. For some moments I felt like I was reading The Phoenix Project to the extent it was describing contemporary professional life …but then drops in a story of using child abuse as a supervisory tactic and that was not enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;hr&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    This book review for &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://island94.org/2022/06/hench&quot;&gt;Hench&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, is published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://island94.org&quot;&gt;Island94.org&lt;/a&gt;.
    Tweet me at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bensheldon&quot;&gt;@bensheldon&lt;/a&gt; to discuss it.
  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
  <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 19:06:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <link>https://island94.org/2022/06/hench</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="true">https://island94.org/2022/06/hench</guid>
</item>

    
      






<item>
  <title>I read &quot;Recoding Gender&quot; by Janet Abbate</title>
  <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;recoding-gender&quot;&gt;Recoding gender&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed the book. It’s a quick survey of early computing and software history, and the lens of gender makes a lot of it new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few themes stuck out to me, from my standpoint of 2022:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Contemporary development, and even agile (by other names) come from feminized sources.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The distinctions between the activities of plugging, coding, programming, solving, planning, and training; and the roles of “Engineer”, or “Architect” or “Manager” which are largely gendered.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The feminization of  “technical” work of interacting with business machines (e.g. a typewriter, photocopier, etc.) and the perceptual “de-skilling” of those roles despite them being, well, heavily technical.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Programming productivity gains being gobbled up by increasing complexity…. Well, sometimes… because there is a perceptual emphasis on complex edge-cases rather than the needs of the “typical” business.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/NATO_Software_Engineering_Conferences&quot;&gt;Conference on Software Engineering sponsored by NATO and held in Garmisch, Germany on 7–11 October 1968&lt;/a&gt; was a big deal in the history of programming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure sounds like contemporary collaborative practices:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;[Elsie] Shutt’s [of Comp Inc.] approach was to organize her programmers in teams that collaboratively divided the work among themselves: “We would get together every week, everybody working on the project. One thing we had to learn to do was to take a job and to break it into pieces—meaningful pieces—and then we’d get together, talk about it, assign jobs.” She coached her programmers to be meticulous, which resulted in efficiencies for the company and a better product for the client. For example, she emphasized desk-checking, the practice of having programmers review each other’s code before running it on the computer. Although desk-checking was a fairly common practice in the 1950s, Shutt believed that she “emphasized it more than others did” because we were doing things that we broke up into more pieces than some people did.” Comp Inc. had no room for “egotistical” programmers who refused the share their code. Another key priority was “documenting it—well—so that someone else would be able to maintain it if they needed to.” Producing modular, well-documented code also made it easier for Comp Inc. to repurpose programs for subsequent clients, which saved on programming costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…and Agile:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Women may have been uniquely situated to participate in these innovations because of their gendered role in the workplace. As working programmers—and as the staff members who stereotypically were asked to assist customers or in-house users—women had both the expertise to devise solutions and the incentive to make programming easier for experts and novices alike. And although women usually lacked the formal authority to impose workplace practices, this was unnecessary in a computer culture that left the choice of techniques largely up to programmers themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On productivity and the never-realized goal of getting rid of programming as a specialization:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In many ways, the campaign for automatic programming was a rousing success: The new techniques were widely adopted, and as promised, they greatly reduced the time that was needed to produce programs and  transferred much tedious work from humans to machines. Many programmers took advantage of these new tools to improve the organization of that programs, creating a visible, logical structure that made code faster to produce and easier to maintain, reuse, and share. However, to the disappointment of some, the overall effect of compilers and associated tools was not to eliminate programming but to redefine it. Much of what had been included as an integral part of programming practice–tedious copying or recoding of subroutines, the need to be aware of machine design and physical memory configuration, and the use of machine codes-was no longer required. But the programmer still had to design and specify the higher-level structure of the program, tasks that proved too complex for most end-users. The new techniques also did nothing to automate the initial analysis of the problem–the task of modeling a real-world activity as an ordered flow of computable steps. Although this work could potentially be shifted from the programmer to a systems analyst, in either case it was a person and not the computer that performed it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;To the extent that a factory-like version of automation failed to materialize, it vindicated programmers’ holistic view of their work as complex and creative. It also reflected a conscious decision by computer manufacturers and their customers to use automation to increase productivity and quality rather than to shrink the labor force. Managers asked programmers to tackle more ambitious projects or create more sophisticated user interfaces, expanding their demand for skilled labor to absorb the available supply. The ever increasing complexity of cutting-edge systems would soon lead to new calls for a reform of programming methods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An ongoing discussion about what happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The term software engineering has become common enough today that its provocative effect has been lost. Yet when the term was introduced at Garmisch, it was purely aspirational.  Rather than claiming to describe actual practices, the organizers named an ideal that did not yet exist. Nor was it obvious that engineering was the best model for programming. The computing literature of the 1960s is rife with competing metaphors, each or which was chosen to make a particular claim about the nature of programming. Some managers continued to view programming as creative art or craft—and in a positive sense, rather than as a problem to Be cured by imposing scientific rationality. In the academic community, computer science was often seen as a branch of mathematics, which had a higher intellectual status than engineering. The 1970 &lt;em&gt;On the Management&lt;/em&gt; of Computer Programming, a book that targeted a business audience, ignored the new term software engineering and preferred to use managerial skill as its ideal. Maurice Wilkes argued in 1976 that the term &lt;em&gt;engineering&lt;/em&gt; did not realistically represent the process of creating a large program. He suggested instead that “There are some analogies between writing a program and writing a treatise or a paper.” Computer industry writers invoked a host of other professions to emulate, including accounting (for its certification standards), medicine (for its skilled teamwork and strong professional societies), architecture (as a model for coherent design and precise specification), aviation (for its recognition of the dire consequences of failure), or even cooking (as a time sensitive production process).&lt;br /&gt;
 …&lt;br /&gt;
Given this gendered status hierarchy, some practitioners—women as well as men—may have believed that programmers would rise in stature by adopting the title of engineer. An unintended consequence of this move may have been to make programming and computer science less inviting to women, helping to explain the historical puzzle of why women took a leading role in the first wave of software improvements but become much less visible in the software engineering era.&lt;br /&gt;
….&lt;br /&gt;
“For instance, getting your requirements right initially; understanding the materials you’re working with.” Susan Graham, the daughter of a mechanical engineer, got her Ph.D. in computer science a few years after Garmisch and easily identified as a software engineer.  Referring to the process of checking the semantics of a programming language, Graham characterized engineering practice as trial-and-error: “You write a compiler, and then you do a lot of testing against real programs, and you try to see whether the right thing happens. And that’s why it’s engineer ing!” These examples demonstrate again the diverse meanings of engineering, as well as female practitioners ability to prioritize those aspects of engineering that matched their own needs, experiences, and values.&lt;br /&gt;
…&lt;br /&gt;
Some aspects of the software engineering ideal appealed directly to preferences that were widely expressed by women, such as the desire to create something that would improve users’ lives. Edward E. David of Bell Laboratories expressed this philosophy at Garmisch in 1968: “Software engineering and computing engineering have an extremely important and nice aspect to them, namely that people want to work on things that meet other people’s needs. They are not interested in working on abstractions entirely; they want to have an impact on the world.” Mary Shaw, who helped establish Carnegie Mellon University’s Software Engineering Institute in the 1980s, echoed this public service ethos in her own 1990 definition of engineering as solving “practical problems . . . in the service of mankind:”In her view, key aspects of an “engineering attitude” included “considering users” and realizing that design choices had to be made “for both technical and nontechnical reasons.’ Shaw’s emphasis  on users and on real-word, nontechnical factors fits well with the computer-as-a-tool orientation more common among women. &lt;strong&gt;Although Engineering as a profession has been highly masculine, engineering as a discipline or philosophy has had wider range of potential meaning.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
… &lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;In at least three important senses, software engineering could be said to have failed.&lt;/strong&gt; First, because of the divergent approaches and priorities of academic theorists and industry practitioners, much research investment has been wasted. Second, to the extent that software engineering was meant to revolutionize labor practices by deskilling and disciplining programmers, imposing standardized research-based methods, or mandating licensing, it has not succeeded. Finally, software engineering never solved the problem that was its &lt;em&gt;raison d’etre&lt;/em&gt;—the software crisis. These failures call into question the notion that engineering is the most appropriate model for the programming profession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;hr&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    This book review for &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://island94.org/2022/04/recoding-gender&quot;&gt;Recoding Gender&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, is published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://island94.org&quot;&gt;Island94.org&lt;/a&gt;.
    Tweet me at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bensheldon&quot;&gt;@bensheldon&lt;/a&gt; to discuss it.
  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
  <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 02:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <link>https://island94.org/2022/04/recoding-gender</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="true">https://island94.org/2022/04/recoding-gender</guid>
</item>

    
      






<item>
  <title>I read &quot;Science in the Capital&quot; by Kim Stanley Robinson</title>
  <description>&lt;p&gt;The series is 3 books:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Forty Signs of Rain&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fifty Degrees Below&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sixty Days and Counting&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was subsequently re-edited into a single edition (&lt;em&gt;Green Earth&lt;/em&gt;), but I read the originals. They have all the components of a KSR book:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Someone is smacked in the face&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The last third of the book/series includes a travelogue of terraforming&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Buddhism&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Humanity rendered (and pondering) their place as a primates-out-of-forest/fish-out-of-water in a technology-based society.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And some uniquely nice and interesting things&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Child characters. I found them the most interesting, especially toddler Joe. Older Nick is pretty boring and unmotivated (in the literary sense) in stark contrast to &lt;em&gt;Aurora&lt;/em&gt;’s Devi.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Contemporary setting (which does have its problems, like suggesting fictional nano-rods instead of actual CRISPR). This is mainly why I gave it 4 stars; it’s fairly unique as a KSR book goes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A main theme is “an excess of reason is itself a form of madness” with the various characters navigating contemporary rationalism (politics, bureaucracy, venture science, healthcare, courtship, family) within the constraints of their character’s authentic selves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“We are animals. Animals whose wisdom has extended so far as to tell us we are mortal creatures. We die. For fifty thousand years we have known this. Much of our mental energy is spent avoiding this knowledge. We do not like to think of it. Then again, we know now that even the cosmos is mortal. Reality is mortal. All things change ceaselessly. Nothing remains the same in time. Nothing can be held on to. The question then becomes, what do we &lt;em&gt;do&lt;/em&gt; with this knowledge? How do we live with it? How do we make sense of it?”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Well—indeed. Frank leaned forward, piqued, wondering what Drepung would tell them the old man had said next. That gravelly low voice, growling through its incomprehensible sounds—it was strange to think it was expressing such meanings. Frank suddenly wanted to know what he was saying.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“One of the scientific terms for compassion,” Drepung said, looking around the ceiling as if for the word, “…  you say, ‘altruism.’ This is a question in your animal studies. Does true altruism exist, and is it a good adaptation? Does compassion work, in other words? You have done studies that suggest altruism is the best adaptive strategy, if seen from the group context. This then becomes a kind of … admonishment. To practice compassion in order to successfully evolve—this, coming from your science, which claims to be descriptive only! Only describing what has worked to make us what we are. But in Buddhism we have always said, if you want to help others, practice compassion; if you want to help yourself, practice compassion. Now science adds, if you want to help your species, practice compassion.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This got a laugh, and Frank also chuckled. He started to think about it in terms of prisoners’ dilemma strategies; it was an invocation for all to make the always generous move, for maximum group return, indeed maximum individual return.… Thus he missed what Drepung said next, absorbed in something more like a feeling than a thought: &lt;em&gt;If only I could believe in something, no doubt it would be a relief&lt;/em&gt;. All his rationality, all his acid skepticism; suddenly it was hard not to feel that it was really just some kind of disorder.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And at that very moment Rudra Cakrin looked right at him, him alone in all the audience, and Drepung said, “An excess of reason is itself a form of madness.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Frank sat back in his seat. What had the question been? Rerunning his short-term memory, he could not find it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Now he was lost to the conversation again. His flesh was tingling, as if he were a bell that had been struck.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“The experience of enlightenment can be sudden.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;He didn’t hear that, not consciously.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“The scattered parts of consciousness occasionally assemble at once into a whole pattern.”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;He didn’t hear that either, as he was lost in thought. All his certainties were trembling. He thought, an excess of reason itself a form of madness—it’s the story of my life. And the old man &lt;em&gt;knew&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The biggest problem with the book is that one of the main characters is super creepy. And it goes on too long. I think the latter is fixed in the edited Green Planet edition, but I dunno about the former.  Fortunately he doesn’t act on it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Now he was considering acting in accordance with his beliefs. Something else he had heard the Khembalis say at the Quiblers, this time Drepung: If you don’t act on it, it wasn’t a true feeling. … One can always just walk away. The Dalai Lama had said that for sure. Things you don’t like, things you think are wrong, you can always just walk away. You will be happier. Love and compassion are necessities, not luxuries. Without them humanity cannot survive. But compassion is not just a feeling. You have to act.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you make it to the third book, you’re treated to some good liberal head-canon in the newly elected President’s inauguration speech:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Fellow Americans,” he said, pacing his speech to the reverb of the loudspeakers, “you have entrusted me with the job of president during a difficult time. The crisis we face now, of abrupt climate change and crippling damage to the biosphere, is a very dangerous one, to be sure. But we are not at war with anyone, and in fact we face a challenge that all humanity has to meet together. On this podium, Franklin Roosevelt said, ‘This generation has a rendezvous with destiny.’ Now it’s true again. We are the generation that has to deal with the profound destruction that will be caused by the global warming that has already been set in motion. The potential disruption of the natural order is so great that scientists warn of a mass extinction event. Losses on that scale would endanger all humanity, and so we cannot fail to address the threat. The lives of our children, and all their descendants, depend on us doing so.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“So, like FDR and his generation, we have to face the great challenge of our time. We have to use our government to organize a total social response to the problem. That took courage then, and we will need courage now. In the years since we used our government to help get us out of the Great Depression, it has sometimes been fashionable to belittle the American government as some kind of foreign burden laid on us. That attitude is nothing more than an attack on American history, deliberately designed to shift power away from the American people. I want us to remember how Abraham Lincoln said it: ‘that government of the people, by the people, and for the people shall not perish from this&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Earth.’ This is the crucial concept of American democracy—that government expresses what the majority of us would like to do as a society. It’s us. We do it to us and for us. I believe this reminder is so important that I intend to add the defining phrase ‘of the people, by the people, and for the people’ every time I use the word ‘government,’ and I intend to do all I can to make that phrase be a true description. It will make me even more long-winded than I was before, but I am willing to pay that price, and you are going to have to pay it with me.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“So, this winter, with your approval and support, I intend to instruct my team in the executive branch of government of the people, by the people, and for the people, to initiate a series of federal actions and changes designed to meet the problem of global climate change head-on. We will deal with it as a society working together, and working with the rest of the world. It’s a global project, and so I will go to the United Nations and tell them that the United States is ready to join the international effort. We will also help the under-developed world to develop using clean technology, so that all the good aspects of development will not be drowned in its bad side effects—often literally drowned. In our own country, meanwhile, we will do all it takes to shift to clean technologies as quickly as possible.”
Phil paused to survey the crowd. “My, it’s cold out here today! You can feel right now, right down to the bone, that what I am saying is true. We’re out in the cold, and we need to change the way we do things. And it’s not just a technological problem, having to do with our machinery alone. The devastation of the biosphere is also a result of there being too many human beings for the planet to support over the long haul. If the human population continues to increase as it has risen in the past, all progress we might make will be overwhelmed.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“But what is very striking to observe is that everywhere on this Earth where good standards of justice prevail, the rate of reproduction is about at the replacement rate. While wherever justice, and the full array of rights as described in the UN Declaration of Human Rights, is somehow denied to some portion of the population, especially to women and children, the rate of reproduction either balloons to unsustainably rapid growth rates, or crashes outright. Now you can argue all you want about why this correlation exists, but the correlation itself is striking and undeniable. So this is one of those situations in which what we do for good in one area, helps us again in another. It is a positive feedback loop with the most profound implications. Consider: for the sake of climate stabilization, there must be population stabilization; and for there to be population stabilization, &lt;em&gt;justice must prevail.&lt;/em&gt; Every person on the planet must live with the full array of human rights that all nations have already ascribed to when signing the UN Charter. When we achieve that, at that point, and at that point only, we will begin to reproduce at a sustainable rate.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“To help that to happen, I intend to make sure that the United States joins the global justice project &lt;em&gt;fully, unequivocally,&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;without any double standards&lt;/em&gt;. This means accepting the jurisdiction of the International Criminal Court, and the jurisdiction of the World Court in the Hague. It means abiding by all the clauses of the UN Charter and the Geneva Conventions, which after all we have already signed. It means supporting UN peacekeeping forces, and supporting the general concept of the UN as the body through which international conflicts get resolved. It means supporting the World Health Organization in all its reproductive rights and population reduction efforts. It means supporting women’s education and women’s rights everywhere, even in cultures where men’s tyrannies are claimed to be some sort of tradition. All these commitments on our part will be crucial if we are serious about building a sustainable world. There are three legs to this effort, folks: technology, environment, and social justice. None of the three can be neglected.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“So, some of what we do may look a little unconventional at first. And it may look more than a little threatening to those few who have been trying, in effect, to buy our government of the people, by the people, and for the people, and use it to line their own pockets while the world goes smash. But you know what? Those people need to change too. They’re out in the cold the same as the rest of us. So we will proceed, and hope those opposed come to see the good in it.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“Ultimately we will be exploring all peaceful means to initiate positive changes in our systems, in order to hand on to the generations to come a world that is as beautiful and bountiful as the one we were born into. We are only the temporary stewards of a mighty trust, which includes the lives of all the future generations to come. We are responsible to our children and theirs. What we do now will reveal much about our character and our values as a people. We have to rise to the occasion, and I think we can and will. I am going to throw myself into the effort wholeheartedly and with a feeling of high excitement, as if beginning a long journey over stormy seas.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;hr&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    This book review for &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://island94.org/2022/04/science-in-the-capital&quot;&gt;Science in the Capital&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, is published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://island94.org&quot;&gt;Island94.org&lt;/a&gt;.
    Tweet me at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bensheldon&quot;&gt;@bensheldon&lt;/a&gt; to discuss it.
  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
  <pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2022 17:32:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <link>https://island94.org/2022/04/science-in-the-capital</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="true">https://island94.org/2022/04/science-in-the-capital</guid>
</item>

    
      






<item>
  <title>I read &quot;Let the Record Show: A Political History of ACT UP New York, 1987-1993&quot; by Sarah Schulman</title>
  <description>&lt;p&gt;I discovered the &lt;a href=&quot;https://actupny.org/documents/documents.html&quot;&gt;ACT UP&lt;/a&gt; organization in the wake of Occupy, when I became friends with Michael Petrellis, who I met through my church.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book is a wonderful approach to documenting an organizing: powerful, tragic, and practical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When preparing the ACT UP Oral History Project, Jim and I looked at two Holocaust archives for guidance. The Shoah Foundation, organized by Steven Spielberg, had a structure that did not fit our needs. Designed to counter Holocaust revisionism, in which people who did not commit the Holocaust deny that it ever occurred, the project had hundreds of interviewers focused on a list of predetermined questions. We felt that the interviews were designed to emphasize the moments of trauma, of oppression and atrocity. As important as this was, we were more intrigued by a small archive financed by the Fortunoff department store family that investigated who each person was before the Holocaust, and then how they were impacted by the turn of events. This approach really appealed to us for a number of reasons. The primary purpose of the ACT UP Oral History Project, and of this book, is not to look back with nostalgia, but rather to help contemporary and future activists learn from the past so that they can do more effective organizing in the present. We wanted to show, clearly, what we had witnessed in ACT UP: that people from all walks of life, working together, can change the world.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;…&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The story of access in ACT UP is the story of a collective that intended to do good, and actually did in fact truly make the world a better place. Inside those accomplishments are realities of a human dimension: people who do great things also do bad things, sometimes out of bias and supremacy, and sometimes out of vulnerability, fear of demise, the desire to live, or all of the above. And when white people, and men, do things out of bias and vulnerability, people with less access pay a price. Sometimes that price is stress, or being forced to strategize, or being blindsided as a way of life. Sometimes that price is exclusion from treatments, from participation in decision-making, or from the machine of power. Sometimes that means death, and sometimes that means long-term and systemic deprivation for the collective as well as the individual. When we evaluate how we have spent our lives, we have to look at our cumulative impact, not at the moments of failure or bad faith. Assessing this history is not a game of call-out. Instead, it is an effort to really understand and make clear how the AIDS rebellion succeeded, and to face where it failed, in order to be more conscious and deliberate, and therefore effective, today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book contains a lot:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Drive and commitment, invention and felicity, a focus on campaigns, and being effective are the components of movements that change the world.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“A small, very crucial group of individuals had spent their time in ACT UP observing and analyzing the full range of meaning and impact of ACT UP as a whole, and developed organizational overviews, which permitted broad analysis, recognition of large tropes, and a grasp of strategic reach. But most often, ACT UP did not theorize itself…. Direct action was a concept by which theoretical discussion was not separate from action. Of course, individual ACT UPers were influenced by theory. A number of young video activists had studied in the Whitney Museum Studio Program. Many older activists came from highly theorized earlier radical movements, and some members, like Douglas Crimp, wrote theory. But on the floor of the Monday-night meeting, theory was never debated unless it was tied to creating actions, or to setting active campaigns. As Maxine Wolfe, one of ACT UP’s most influential leaders, would say, when planning and carrying out an action, “theory emerges” as a concrete result of actual decisions that are being made for real-life application. Instead of the Gramscian concept of “praxis,” which is the application of theory into practice, ACT UP first chose a practice—an action—and then evolved a theory necessary to make it work toward our larger goal of “direct action to end the AIDS crisis.” &lt;strong&gt;In this way campaigns were structured as a series of interconnected actions, designed to produce a larger outcome. ACT UP would never just do a demonstration, zap, or action to stand on its own. These public expressions were designed to build to the next step. That’s why every event had a sign-up sheet, or leaflets announcing further actions, and participants were informed of the next step in the series on any specific issue. Every action included a component of giving participants and observers something else to do. In this way, energy was not wasted, and events had purpose, as part of a larger schema. Not wasting energy, effort, or goodwill was essential to being effective in a movement of people who literally did not have time.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Gregg got together with Charles Stimson and Ortez Alderson, an activist from Chicago who had moved to New York to become an actor and who was working in Black gay theater with Assotto Saint. They decided to get together to “do a kind of activism that was not necessarily authorized by the large group.” They were annoyed by what they felt was a slow pace as ACT UP grappled to develop their perspective. They called themselves “MHA,” which actually didn’t stand for anything, but had flexible uses. For example, they used “Metropolitan Health Association” in order to get a meeting with Stephen Joseph, the health commissioner of New York City. At that time, Joseph was talking about various kinds of punitive measures against prostitutes. He had engaged in some “very panic-causing kinds of rhetoric” about the threat that people with AIDS, for whom he was considering internment and other repressive measures, caused to the general public, particularly around tuberculosis. MHA showed up. “We said, ‘We’re the Metropolitan Health Association.’ They said, ‘Please come in.’” They were in a large conference room with Stephen Joseph. It quickly became apparent, though, that MHA was not any kind of interborough health consortium. They started asking Joseph about the slow pace in the city’s response to AIDS. When Joseph realized that they were AIDS activists, Gregg and company were arrested and the story appeared in the press. At the next ACT UP meeting, Gregg remembers rising and saying, &lt;strong&gt;“Look, you can just do this. You don’t have to go to the large group to get authorization. In fact, it’s better that the large group is not involved with these kinds of actions because they don’t have to be held accountable. So you can just do stuff. ACT UP is just this place we all meet on a weekly basis to talk about strategy and prioritize issues.”&lt;/strong&gt; He remembered saying over and over again, You can just do this. Just go out and do this. And people were very enthusiastic. This happened at the same time that the concept of affinity groups, which were inherently autonomous from the larger body, was gaining more popularity in ACT UP.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“I remember having this kind of conscious realization that if you stood up and said exactly what you meant and didn’t trail off into some kind of rambling incoherence, which is often the style of many people in meetings, that actually your opinion would be respected or at least heard.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“The Media Committee’s job was to make sure the press covered the action. How do you get the press to pay attention? Ann laid out the fundamental points of doing media for a radical political movement: Well, first of all, you do plan an action that is interesting enough, that you think the press is going to care about it. But you have to woo the press. You have to find a way to get them there. Some of that is about writing a press release that you send to the press that’s interesting enough to make them look at it and say, Oh, I better go cover that—that’s going to be important or interesting or crazy, and will make good pictures and put wild people on television. But we also know that the press doesn’t generally read press releases, so don’t expect to get the press there, just by sending them a press release, because they’re going to throw it in the wastebasket, and you’re just going to have to do it all over again. So you have to call them. And you have to find the right person to speak to. So you have to know how to call a newspaper or television station and say—not ask to speak to a specific person, but say—I’m calling about this, who should I speak to? And let them tell you who to speak to. Then you have to know how to talk to that person, and how to present [the issue]. And you do it first by asking them questions, and saying, What do you know about this? What’s your opinion of such and such? Rather than just throwing something at them. And then, lead them into being interested about this, and say, Well, what you may not know is such and such. Or, We’re doing this, that you might find interesting, and sort of make them think it’s their idea to come do this, rather than haranguing them or lecturing them about—You should be there, and you should be covering this. That will make them sit home, guaranteed. Part of infiltrating the media’s messaging was through simple education, in the hopes of getting our message, and not the state’s, or the corporation’s, across. “The press was so stupid and so lazy, that they would come to every demonstration and ask one question: Why are you here? That was it. And they had no understanding of any issue, and no ability to ask questions about any issue. Ninety-five percent of any news story is what the reporter is saying. The sound bites are a very tiny part of any story. I would tell people, Watch the evening news, and time how much of a story is the reporter’s narration, and how much is the sound bite, and you’ll find that the sound bite is a very small portion of the story. So it’s far less important for you to come up with the right sound bite than it is for you to talk to the reporter before they do the story and educate them, so they will reflect your point of view in their narration.”…“And one of her well-known insights is that you’re not talking to the media, you’re talking through the media.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Like many women in ACT UP, Anne-Christine came from the reproductive rights movement, which heavily influenced her perspective on AIDS activism. “I actually think it was the closest to the reproductive rights work, because it was the angriest. People in reproductive rights were really angry. I didn’t think the people in the peace movement were as angry at all. I thought that they were sort of morally high ground in the peace movement, but I don’t feel like there was the same direct stake. And I think with AIDS, it was such a direct thing, because people were terrified … Coming out of Haiti, where a lot of people had died and were dying, it felt much more urgent to me. And so it was compelling in that way”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“There were two groups of people in ACT UP. There were the groups of people who thought that until they had AIDS, they thought that the government was out there, and working for them. And I went to an affinity group meeting with this guy, I don’t remember his name; and he said it, quite clear. And he was really serious. He said, I can’t believe that my government let me down. I had a good job, I had plenty of money. But when I got sick, the government let me down. I wasn’t getting the services, I got treated like a pariah. Then there was the other group—and it wasn’t only people of color; but there’s another group, I think it’s more of a class thing—who knew that the system stunk, and the system had been letting them down, for years … People with insurance were definitely feeling something different than people going in with Medicaid … There were people that socialized in ACT UP who would never, ever, in a million years, if it wasn’t that situation, even talk to each other on the street. “But I think that’s the thing that held the group together so long, and made it work. Even people you didn’t like in ACT UP, right—you would support them in some way, because you had the same issues … People were dying, it was urgent; a lot of people in the group were dying; and this was it. There was nowhere else to go but ACT UP. And I think some people came to ACT UP or they would have jumped out windows if they didn’t come to ACT UP, because it was also, in a way, some kind of therapy for people coming there. Whether you were rich or poor, that was one of the only places you could talk about your condition, your friend’s condition, whoever you were taking care of. That was the only place to talk about it. And I think that made an alliance that would have never happened anywhere else … And the anger was there. Everybody was pissed. They weren’t getting the services; most people were still treated like pariahs, in the beginning.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“And so César articulates for us that ACT UP and its relationships are, as Matt Brim notes, not just a model of activism but a model of making sense of the problem that activism is trying to address, and the problem that lingers in the lives of individuals, long after the activism creates some kind of positive permanent change. Activism is, consequentially, the process of making sense of one’s experience of the problem that collectively we have transformed. It creates order, demystifies, and allows an understanding of systems that otherwise feel overwhelming and unaddressable.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;hr&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    This book review for &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://island94.org/2022/03/let-the-record-show-a-political-history-of-act-up-new-york,-1987-1993&quot;&gt;Let the Record Show: A Political History of ACT UP New York, 1987-1993&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, is published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://island94.org&quot;&gt;Island94.org&lt;/a&gt;.
    Tweet me at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bensheldon&quot;&gt;@bensheldon&lt;/a&gt; to discuss it.
  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
  <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2022 16:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <link>https://island94.org/2022/03/let-the-record-show-a-political-history-of-act-up-new-york,-1987-1993</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="true">https://island94.org/2022/03/let-the-record-show-a-political-history-of-act-up-new-york,-1987-1993</guid>
</item>

    
      






<item>
  <title>I read &quot;Bullshit Jobs&quot; by David Graeber</title>
  <description>&lt;p&gt;Recommended by Rob, and part of a milieu that also included &lt;em&gt;The Real World of Technology&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Breaking Stuff at Work&lt;/em&gt; with a synthesis along the lines of “technology squeezes the lower-middle manager roles (sergeant/foreman), not the upper managers”. But that’s not what Bullshit Jobs is about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from the essay, the best part for me was a description of how we haven’t replaced the feudal system, just layered onto it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has some critical bits about open source being the fun bits done for free, and the paid job is unsatisfying duct taping it together. Which doesn’t track for my immediate experience (at least not what is blame on &lt;em&gt;open source&lt;/em&gt; specifically), but the lines between “analyst/integrator” and “engineer” is real mushy sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a quick read, and I think is good contemporary cannon (aside: I wonder what Rushkoff is up to?). Besides briefly and self-consciously touching on UBI, it left me with an anxious “Yep!” that maybe didn’t need 350 pages to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;This is a powerful argument for human freedom. Most of us like to talk about freedom in the abstract, even claim that it’s the most important thing for anyone to fight or die for, but we don’t think a lot about what being free or practicing freedom might actually mean. The main point of this book was not to propose concrete policy prescriptions, but to start us thinking and arguing about what a genuine free society might actually be like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There was quite a bit about feminization of work:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;One might say that men will always take for themselves the kind of jobs one can tell stories about afterward, and try to assign women the kind you tell stories during.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And distinctions between Michel Foucault’s power and domination (or Sarah Schulman’s conflict and abuse):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;…unlike actual BDSM play, where there’s always a safe-word, when “normal” people fall into the same dynamic, there’s never such an easy way out. “You can’t say ‘orange’ to your boss.” It’s always occurred to me this insight is important and could even become the basis for a theory of social liberation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;hr&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;
    This book review for &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://island94.org/2022/03/bullshit-jobs&quot;&gt;Bullshit Jobs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, is published on &lt;a href=&quot;https://island94.org&quot;&gt;Island94.org&lt;/a&gt;.
    Tweet me at &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/bensheldon&quot;&gt;@bensheldon&lt;/a&gt; to discuss it.
  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
  <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 22:20:00 +0000</pubDate>
  <link>https://island94.org/2022/03/bullshit-jobs</link>
  <guid isPermaLink="true">https://island94.org/2022/03/bullshit-jobs</guid>
</item>

    
  </channel>
</rss>
